PRAYER TIME
Say in the name of Jesus, you demon, OUT!!!!
Out!
Command them to come out right now.
I am his wife.
What have you done to him?
I made him useless.
What have you done to his career?
He can't do anything, he can't progress - nothing.
How did you enter him?
I make love to him.
Many nights when he is about to meet his success, I make love to him
and just render him useless.
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Children of God, Emmanuel!
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Daniel, and the lady standing beside me is my mum.
I was delivered from a spiritual wife.
It all started when things got rough
so we had to relocate back to the village.
I went to sit for my WAEC exams.
I was an external student.
There was this day I was walking out with my friend, going back to school.
A man - a priest because he wore a white cassock - stopped his car.
He pointed out to my friend and said, "Come!"
I was thinking it was my friend so I pushed my friend forward
and said, "You are the one he is calling".
My friend stepped forward, and he said, "No, not you - him!"
So I came and he spoke to me.
I didn't know him so I just wanted to be nice.
I greeted him and he asked me what I was doing there
and I told him I came for an exam.
He told me that I was good looking
and he wanted to know me later.
He was like, could he get my number.
At first I just wanted to walk away but I stayed back just to be polite.
I gave him my number and that is how the whole thing started.
From time to time, he called to check up and there was this day
that he finally invited me over to his place.
That is when he made advances at me
and I was shocked because I know priests represent God.
Like servants here on earth.
I was seeing the different side of this person.
When he made advances at me, I wanted to walk away.
He pulled me back and said that it was alright, that if I didn't want to,
it was no problem, he was not in a rush.
For the benefit of the viewers all over the world, what do you mean
by 'he made advances at you' - what did that actually mean?
He tried to kiss me.
To have an affair with you?
Yes, he tried to have an affair with me.
That is, man to man?
Yes, man to man.
I saw it as insane, but I couldn't say anything then.
Have you had such an experience before in your life?
No. Never.
I told him that I couldn't do that and
he told me that it was okay, he was not in a hurry,
that it takes time and all that.
I left.
When I came back home, my friend asked me what had happened, if he gave me something.
I said, "Nothing, I just went to see him".
What age were you by that time?
I was at 20, 22.
He called again. I was like I was never to go back there again.
I slept and had a dream.
There were these people surrounding me - they were many.
It was like an island.
I was there, they were dancing, doing all sorts of things.
I woke up because I was shocked;
it was the first time I had such a dream.
I couldn't tell anybody; I just went along with it.
So it was after this encounter you had with the man that you had this dream?
Yes.
So what happened after the dream?
I woke up. I couldn't tell anybody, not even my mum.
I couldn't call to tell them.
Despite the fact that we were brought up in the way of the Lord,
I was like - let it be.
It is a normal dream.
The next time he called, I found that I didn't hesitate.
He asked me to come over and I went to his place.
He made the same advances at me and I played along.
But we did not have serious intimacy.
So as I left, he came to me and said that I would have to come some other time.
Time and time went and it kept being like that.
I managed to gain favors from him
and I went on with the whole thing, and I felt it was 'cool'.
That is how it was and after I left school -
I was done with the WAEC exams and left - he kept on calling.
The distance was already there and we couldn't meet.
Every time he called and asked me to come over,
I resisted, saying I had things to do
because every time I left the house,
I had to explain where I was going to or what I was going to do.
So that connection was cut short.
I then wrote the JAM exams and I passed - I had 241.
We were actually preparing for other exams when my brother called.
He said he wanted me to come over to Ghana because he is based there.
My mother said that I had to go to school first,
but my dad said, "Let him go, it's better this way".
He explained to me that whenever I am together with my brother, I can do better.
So we abandoned the fact that I had to go to school
and I went to Ghana.
I stayed with my brother there.
That is when I met someone who had the 'same thing' as me because this person...
We want to be carried along.
So when you travelled to Ghana, you lost contact with this first man
and you said you met a person with the 'same thing' -
what is that thing?
The person whom I met was the owner of the place where we stayed in Ghana.
At first he was like a friend.
He does business with my brother.
You mean he also had the spirit of man?
Yes, he also had that spirit in him.
So then, we always talked, he developed this interest in me.
It went on and when I started having problems
with my brother because of that spirit and left,
that is when he opened up to me who he was.
At that period, I was at his place and he made advances and we went intimate.
It kept on being like that.
It happened each time when I was in the midst of getting something,
when I was walking towards something,
when I 'went down' with a man, the whole thing crumbled.
I found myself sleeping with women in the dream.
I didn't have much in the physical but in my spiritual life,
I found myself owning cars and stuffs and all that.
I slept with a lot of women; they used different faces
of people I know or people I must have seen somewhere.
And that is how every thing I put my hands on crumbled.
I couldn't stay because that spirit was always pushing me to move forward.
So I couldn't stay, because each time I am in a place and they like to turn on...
Because my brother is the type who is always listening to ministration,
he is always watching Emmanuel TV.
Each time he watched it, I just walked away
because I didn't want to be there.
What would make you walk away from watching Emmanuel TV?
My body became very very hot.
Why?
I can't really say because each time I sat down and they prayed, especially the mass prayer,
it happened every time there was a prayer.
By that time, what spirit was in you?
At that period, I had this spirit to sleep with men.
Because of that spirit of man in you,
when you saw Emmanuel TV prayer going on,
you couldn't stay, you always walked away, is that right?
Yes, I couldn't stay because I felt that my whole body was very very hot.
So because of this urge in you,
how did you meet with fellow men that you often went out with,
and how did you identify when you saw people that had the same spirit
that you were having - the spirit of man?
It happened that each time I went out, my relationship with females was lesser,
my relationship with men was more than with females.
Each time I met with someone who had that same spirit,
that spirit of being with a man,
it's easy because 'the devil does know the devil'.
Each time I was with someone, friends, men,
and I saw someone who had the same spirit -
at first I would sit and admire, that is what I did;
and if the person admired back,
it meant that we are game, so I would step out and we would talk.
We would just have a normal discussion.
Then we break - the person breaks up and tells me who he is or he likes men.
and I equally expose myself by telling the person that I equally like men.
Okay. Did you get any form of payment for going out with men like yourself
or did you actually get paid, and what were the caliber of men you went out with?
OK, I went out with high-class boys;
those were the kind of guys that every normal boy of my age would want.
You would see them out there and say,
"Wow! I would like this kind of person".
I didnt't get paid for it all the time.
I just got favors from them.
They would say, "I will do this for you".
After the whole thing, after we had slept together,
they would say that they would do this for me.
I didn't get to ask.
What happened when you were at school?
Tell us more about your school life.
Then I came back to Nigeria, and I had to start all over again.
I met a friend who was a banker.
He was the one who actually talked me into going back to school.
That was when I was looking for a job.
I met him and he wanted to help me.
After I got admission, he was helping me out.
He equally had the same spirit in him.
He had the spirit of being with a man.
He was always helping me out
and things like that happened.
I found out that each time I got upset, there was nobody that could control me.
Nobody could talk me out of it or get to calm me down.
So all along, your parents didn't know you were living this life?
No, nobody except me. I kept it to myself.
I just didn't want to tell anybody who I was then.
So when you went to school, did you get involved into other things,
apart from meeting with fellow men like yourself?
Yes, even then, when I got admission, my mum took me to a church where they prayed for me.
The prophet there prophesied to me that he sees me joining a cult,
that they will lure me into a cult.
It didn't just stop there because when I went to school,
I was always upset and I always wanted more.
So I went out and I was with a friend -
in our lodge, you got to find different kinds of people.
In that place where I stayed, you got to find drug addicts, prostitutes.
So I was there in a school and I was equally working as of then.
Working and schooling wasn't easy because I was a regular student.
I had to do like three weeks at work and one week at school
so I couldn't concentrate.
I was with my friend one day, and we were drinking.
I used to drink and do drugs; I did hard drugs.
I did codeine, and all that.
I smoked weed.
I didn't smoke normal cigarettes as any other person would want to do.
I got to do hard drugs.
I did tramadol, I did so many of them.
Have your parents ever heard of this?
No, they haven't.
So your mother is hearing this for the first time?
My mum is actually hearing this for the first time.
And it happened that way.
I was with a friend one day, and he asked me to accompany him somewhere.
Then we were 'high', 'stoned'.
We were trying to calm ourselves down.
We were 'stoned' and he talked to me and I played along.
I went out with him and I didn't know where he was actually taking me.
He was always telling me -
each time he saw me upset and I got to calm down -
he was always telling me that he saw a great person in me.
That is when I joined the cult.
It is a popular cult.
I joined, and on the day of initiation, I was taken to the ground -
they call it 'the arena ground'.
I was taken there.
We were so many and we had to bow our heads down.
We didn't see each other, we couldn't see, it was dark.
The whole place was dark.
We were taken, we were all beaten for seven good hours;
we were beaten very hard with logs.
Some people passed out in the process,
some died because it was not easy
for you to stand a 7 hours torture - nobody,
no matter how strong you are.
I found out that then, I felt no pain.
I was there, I took the whole thing for 7 good hours.
After the whole thing they gave me the name.
They said it's a strong name that is always there to guide me,
that the person who had the name before was a strong person.
So that spirit commanded to do things.
So what was the name you were given in the cult?
I was actually called 'Field Marshal Idi Amin Dada'.
It's a strong name.
So I never used to answer my own name.
They said it's the Jew name.
So I would not be known, we wouldn't get to address ourselves,
except we were in the public so that we wouldn't expose ourselves.
So can you tell us some of those activities that you partook in
when you joined the cult
and what was your position in the cult?
The name given to me was a name of someone
who was actually stronger than I was.
I was actually being groomed to take the person's position.
Nobody knows about that.
So I never used to go to school, I would drink, I would party a lot.
Every time I woke up and wanted to go to work, I was 'stoned'.
I was stoned, I had to take my bath so many times.
When I got to work, nobody would notice, I just acted normal.
So all this while, your parents thought you were in the school studying?
All this while, they thought I was in school studying.
My mum called because I am closer to my mum,
and I know right now she feels so disappointed in me.
Evey time she called and asked if I prayed...
I never used to go to church.
There was nothing you could tell me about God that I wanted to listen.
Why would I want to go to church when I had a swell time
smoking and getting stoned,
getting to see a lot of girls.
Where would I get the time to worship and focus on God?
So it wasn't there.
A lot of my time was spent in the club and with friends
who we went out with doing bad things.
So what happened later?
At school, at the initiation ground, I was asked to do something,
we took an oath.
We were asked how many people we would kill for the cult.
If you were asked that question, you would just say that you will kill many.
And with that oath you were expected to do what you promised to them.
I was given my own pistol. I have a picture of it on my phone.
I went on with that - no school.
The painful part is that they were believing I was in school,
but I wasn't in school.
I was just working, that is what I told myself
because from January till today I don't even own a dime to myself
because I spent everything there.
The least I know I payed for were my textbooks.
And as for my school fees - I used them to purchase a pistol for myself.
So then the heat was too much because you got to see rivals from other cults.
So while they were still grooming me, I was playing along.
At the end of the day, I would be better than the person who had this name before,
and I would do many things for them,
so that was the promise I made.
What actually lured me back to them was that I was a fraudster -
that is what I used to do.
Working with them - what actually brought me to my friend,
was when he told me that if I were with them, I would get more connections.
And in no time would I get my own car and house - comfortably,
and I would get to take care of who I want to take care of.
That is what actually took me in,
and he saw that spirit to command,
that ability to do many things for the cult.
We were always given tools to work,
I had a camera - a webcam,
a recorded video of both a male and a female.
So we wrote to people and browsed on the internet
and we would tell them different stories.
If I used a female camera, I made the guy to come after me,
and he would want to meet me.
And I would tell him that I am busy - just to give him an excuse.
So you posed as a female by using a video or pictures of a female?
Yes.
I owned a female video and several pictures of her.
I used it to work - each time they told me that they wanted to see me,
I would pose and give them a video cam - a recorded cam.
There was a software I used to play the cam.
When you were looking at me, you wouldn't see me
that is playing the cam, you would get to watch the recorded cam.
So what did you get from these people at the end of the day -
those that you succeeded in deceiving?
We gave them bills, we dealt with them.
We knew that it was not possible appearing before the person physically.
We told the person that we were going to send the person our package,
our personal belongings to them,
for them to believe that we were actually coming.
Each time we told them that, we would send fake stuffs or fake documents to them to make them believe
and they payed for the belongings.
You have defrauded a lot of people through this means?
Yes.
Okay, tell us as a result of the cult activities,
what did that lead you to? Are you still in school today?
What was happening to your life before this deliverance?
Before this deliverance, I couldn't stay at school anymore because
the rival cult came against the cult that I used to be with
and I was still being groomed.
I didn't know much, I only knew the basics,
I only knew little things
but I was groomed for something, that's all I knew.
But I owned a pistol.
So you dropped out of school at the end of the day?
Yes.
So what was life like before you came for this deliverance?
I dropped out of school because I didn't pay the school fees.
I used my fees to purchase an arm for myself.
When you came to The SCOAN, tell us what happened.
I had to leave school, I lost the job that I was doing.
I came back to Lagos because I talked to a director of mine and he told me that
he was going to get me a job here in Lagos.
I came to Lagos with a mind of getting a job.
I didn't tell anybody what had happened,
the least I told them is that there was a hit and I was beaten badly
and I had to leave school.
I came back to Lagos thinking I was going to get a job.
My friend who talked me into coming here told me that I should come to church,
believing God that I would get something after I confessed.
And last Sunday during the mass prayer, what happened to you?
At the mass prayer when they started praying, I couldn't control myself.
I noticed that my entire body was so hot.
Even the building was too hot.
The man sitting beside me was equally hot,
so I told him that he should excuse me I wanted to pee.
He said, "You cannot go anywhere, that is how it starts,
and you get to miss your deliverance".
I was there and I got so upset. I just wanted to unleash it on him.
So I sat down quietly and the next thing I heard a voice saying,
"Just keep calm, it's just a normal thing and nothing is going to happen".
During the ministration of the Morning Water I was sitting at the back.
It wasn't even my turn, the Morning Water was being ministered to someone else.
I was feeling too hot.
I wasn't feeling comfortable in my own clothes.
When the evangelist stepped forward to me,
I just lost it, I couldn't remember anything.
The only thing I noticed was that I woke up and I saw myself on the floor.
Quite embarrassing but I stood there because I was helpless and
I knew all this while something was wrong with me
because there was nothing I ever did that worked out.
Each time someone wanted to help me I ended up
making love with a strange lady in my dream and I would lose all of it.
I got angry so easily and no one could control me.
I had known that there was something wrong with me
and I had always wanted to get out.
And since after your deliverance can you tell us -
what is your condition now, what are the signs of a delivered person?
Before my deliverance, my Christian life was zero.
There was nothing to write home about concerning my Christian life.
I didn't go to church, I didn't read the Bible.
Now, I own a Bible - it's quite shocking.
I could not pray. If you asked me to pray, I would just murmur and that was the end.
But now I can pray, I get to read my Bible more - I read it daily.
It's a different thing.
Do you still have the urge to meet men like yourself?
No, sir.
I don't really have such urge.
I am free because I feel so light.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So, Mama, we welcome you, in Jesus' name.
Can you introduce yourself?
Your son has said so much about his past life,
We just want to confirm what you knew about your son in the past
and tell us what has been happening in his life before today,
now you are giving this testimony.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Mrs Cassandra.
The young man standing next to me is my son.
Actually, like he said, I brought them up in a Christian way.
In a God fearing manner.
I am so surprised and shocked today
about all he has been saying.
All this confession he is making, you are hearing it for the very first time now?
Yes.
Like he said, whenever he was out of the house,
I would make sure to ask him if he prays.
Even when he went to Ghana, while he was in Accra, Ghana,
I told him that Emmanuel TV is there in Accra, Ghana,
that he should try and locate where The SCOAN was
so that he could always go there for the service.
But to no avail.
So your son was truly a bad boy in the past?
Yes, I would say that because we were formerly in Lagos here,
but when we relocated to Anambra state,
my husband bought the decoder.
And whenever we were watching Emmanuel TV,
he didn't like watching with us.
As soon as everybody went to sleep,
that is when he came to the parlor.
Or sometimes he stayed watching with us and he was sleeping.
I cautioned him many times.
As soon as everybody went to sleep,
he would tune over to those vampire films.
Sometimes when he was just playing with his siblings in the house,
he would scare them with words and animal kind of looks.
Each time when the siblings were complaining, I would complain too.
And when he went to Ghana, he did the same thing - he was not going to church.
When he finally came back here, he got admission to go back to school.
He got admission in Imo state.
While he was schooling, he was working as well.
Every time I asked him, maybe he would call to say one thing or the other -
I would ask him, if he payed his tithe.
I would tell him, "You have to tithe, if you tithe that is what you will use to hold on to God".
Because of time, can you tell us -
ever since your son has been delivered, what are the attitudes you noticed
in him since his deliverance?
After his deliverance last Sunday,
he even bought himself a Bible, he reads his Bible, he prays.
By Gods grace, he is a changed person.
And how does that make you feel as a mother?
I am happy as a mother.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Thank you. What word of advice do you have for youth like you?
Many are into the same addiction and cult activities
that you have been delivered from.
Just in a word, what advice do you have for them?
Before I give my word of advice unto the world,
I would want to use this opportunity
to plead on everybody to help me to beg my mum.
I know I have brought so much pain.
I know she is finding it difficult to believe that this is the person
she has always believed in.
I'm so sorry, mum!
Daniel & Mother - Deliverance Testimony
It's okay, I forgive you.
Mama, we just want to let you know,
on behalf of the anointed man of God, Senior Prophet T.B. Joshua,
the Bible says, if you fail to realize that demons are the ones
that cause people to be bowed down in bondage, you are fighting the wrong battle.
So all that he did in the past, he has disappointed you,
he has walked in the wrong way and lived a bad life in the past
is all as a result of this evil spirit that has tormented him,
even though he has played a role in finding himself in that.
Anyone can be a victim.
Thank God you are here today to stand side by side with your son
to testify that he is a changed person now.
So the past is over.
Your son is no longer the person he used to be,
now he is a new person in Christ Jesus.
The Bible says, "We forgive because we need to be forgiven"
and we thank God that you have forgiven your son, is that right?
Yes, I have.
So how do you show that you have forgiven your son?
Hallelujah, put your hands together for Jesus!
So we thank God for everything.
Brother, your mum has forgiven you as a Christian
and now you know that you have a role to play
to prove yourself as good child again.
And that you can only do by making the Word of God the standard for your life.
Get closer to Jesus and allow His Word to influence you.
And by so doing, your life is totally reformed and
your future in Christ Jesus is guaranteed.
And just one word of advice for people before you leave.
My word of advice to young people like me,
who have been brought up in a Christian home
and you have a mum that is close to you.
Try to talk to her.
If you find any difficulties in anything - your studies, your personal life -
it's best you open up to your parents
because they are the gods we have here on earth.
They are more like guardians to us,
they are like servants of God given to us children.
My advice to young people out there is
whatever you see out there -
like if I were out there living my life like the way I used to live
and you would want to be like me -
stop admiring people for who they are
and pray to be what God wants you to be.
Thank you. Let us put our hands together for Jesus!
Thank you very much. That says it all.
Stop admiring people on the outside
for who they are, or what they are,
but just try to be what God wants you to be.
We congratulate you for this deliverance
and we pray that God Almighty will give you the inner grace
to make the Word of God the standard for your life
and we believe that you are coming back to give a greater testimony
of what God Almighty will begin to do in your life,
your future and career through this deliverance, in Jesus' name.
Amen.